Inventory of the Jones and Bradby Family Papers 1921-1923
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Jones and Bradby Family Papers 1921-19231921-1923
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2004.22
2.00
Primarily letters, postcards, and receipts, mostly from the period 1921-1923 of an African-American family living in Lightfoot, Va. Family members included Signor Bradby, Elizabeth Bradby, Annie Bradby and there are papers relating to Willmore Jones, John Jones, and other Jones family members. Several transactions with the firm of J.A. Bozarth of Williamsburg are present.
Bradby, Signor arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 04/22/2004.
Biographical Note
Member of a Lightfoot, Virginia family. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Signor Bradby.
Scope and Contents
Primarily letters, postcards, and receipts, mostly from the period 1921-1923 of an African-American family living in Lightfoot, Va. Family members included Signor Bradby, Elizabeth Bradby, Annie Bradby and there are papers relating to Willmore Jones, John Jones, and other Jones family members. Several transactions with the firm of J.A. Bozarth of Williamsburg are present.
Arrangement of Materials
Collection is arranged in chronological order.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Topical Term:
African Americans--History--20th century.; Virginia--History--20th century.; Williamsburg (Va.)--History--20th century.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Letters, postcards, receipts., 1872-1888, 17 items. (1)
  County tax receipts, sales receipts, notarized register of payments on a land sale; letters include a 1887 hand-written letter from Barham and Pollard to Mr. John Jones concerning the purchase of peanuts and a promissory note from Robert Carter to John Jones for a debt of $5.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, 1890-1900, 28 items. (2)
  Letters, receipts, a ledger book for the years 1898 and 1899, a land deed, promissory notes; letters include: to Willmore Jones from Samuel Baker [?], to Ja[mes] Jones from Bouren Abersery [?], from R.A. Watkins to John Jones, from Willmore Jones to "My Dear mother", from Robert Morris to "My Dear sister" Mrs. Margret ani [?] Jones, from M.V. Morris to "Dear Cousin" Willmore Jones, from Sarah Dandridge to "My Dear Cousin", from Sislie areen Hurad [?] to "My Dear father" John Jones, from "your son" John M. to John Jones; two letters from Mirtive Jones [John M. Jones?] to his father John Jones, 5 letters from Willmore Jones to "My Dear father" John Jones.
- Letters, postcards, receipts., 1901-1917, 18 items (3)
  Letters, receipts, and mail-order correspondences; letters include: to "My Dear father" from Willmore Jones, to "My Dear Sister Mary" from Lucy Ashby, two 1908 postcards to Annie Bradby from Richard, incomplete letter to "Nannie" from unknown, to Signor Bradby from Edward Pettitt concerning payment on an account, to "Bro. Bradby" from FT & Ashley [?], from Nanie B. Jones at Central State Hospital in Petersburg, VA to Elizabeth Bradby, two 1917 letters to Signor Bradby from W. Walker Ware concerning payment past due on a promissory note.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, 1918-1920, 26 items. (4)
  Letters, receipts, and invoices; letters include: to "Dear Sister" from "your Sester Mary", to "Dear Sister" from "Sister Mary E. Tyler", postcard to Elizabeth Bradby from M.E. LP [?], to "Mr. Segar Bradby" from D.L. Miller concerning the sale of a dog, to "My dear nannie" from Luria Bayton, postcard to Mr. and Mrs. Signor Bradby from unknown. 26 items.
- Letters, postcards, receipts., January 1921-September 1921 (5)
  Letters, receipts, invoices, and mail-order correspondences; letters include: postcard to Elizabeth Bradby from "Your Cousin" Marguarete Walker, to "Seager Bradby from W.F. Cox & Bro. concerning the price of pine wood, postcard to Annie Bradby from L.D. Jones, to Signor Bradby from F.R. Savage of Peninsula Bank & Trust concerning a $95 note endorsed for Andrew Jones that is now past due, to Signor Bradby from J.W. Avery about measuring wood, to "Mr. Bradly" from Lh [?] F Hudgins..
- Letters, postcards, receipts, October 1921-December 1921, 18 items. (6)
  Letters, receipts, and invoices, a deposit slip from the Pennsylvania Bank and Trust Co., a certificate from the Emancipation Club authorizing Signor Bradby to solicit funds; letters include: postcard to Signor Bradby from the Emancipation Committee, to Mr. and Mrs. S. Bradby from F.E. Puryear of the Supreme Lodge Knight of Gideon, to "My Dearest of Friends" from Mrs. Ruth What? [?], postcard to Mr. and Mrs. S. Bradby from F.E. Puryear, postcard to Annie Bradby from E. H. Wise, postcard to "Miss Elizabeth Brodly" from Elizabeth Dandridge [cousin], postcard to "Mrs. Annie Bradsbury" from Rosa Jones.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, March 1922-May 1922, 16 items. (7)
  Letters, receipts, and invoices, a tax notice for $11.60; letters include: to “Sijer Bradbery” from G.J. Jones, to Annie Bradby from Fannie and Henry, to “Miss Lizbeth Bradley” from Nanie B. Jones at Central State Hospital in Petersburg, VA, postcard to Elizabeth Bradby from Emma Wallace, postcard to “Sijer Bradbery” from G. J. Jones.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, July 1922-September 1922, 17 items. (8)
  Letters and receipts; letters include: to “Dear Cousin Signor” from Etta, to Annie Bradby from Florence Haywood, to Signor Bradby from F.R. Savage of Peninsula Bank & Trust concerning a $15 balance past due on an endorsed note for Andrew Jones, to “Signor Bradsby” from C.C. Branch concerning two notes past due, to Annie Bradby from J.L. Freeman, to “Dear sister” from Mary Tyler, postcard to Berkley Lee Jones from “your mother Annie B. Bradby”, to Signor Bradby from “your Cousin Etta”, to “Mrs. Nanie Bradby” “My dear Sister” from Ella Dandridge, to Signor Bradby from Bessie Cumber, to “Mrs. Nannie Bradby” from “sister Annie”, postcard to Signor Bradby from “Cousin Etta”, to “The Perry G. Mason” from “Miss Elizabeth L. Bradby” concerning the order of a dinner set, postcard to Annie Bradby from N.B. Eltin [?], to “My dear Mrs. Bradby” from Adele A. Beverly.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, June 1922, 8 items. (9)
  Letters and mail-order correspondences; letters include: to “Mr. Badby Dear Sis” from “a friend S.L. Pierer, to Annie Bradby from Florence Haywood, to “Dearest Aunt Nannie” from Marie S. Dandridge, to Signor Bradby from “Your Cousin, E.M. Canaday”, to Signor Bradby from “your Cousin Eugene M. Canaday, DDS”, to Annie Bradby from Jen, to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth about a shipment of wood.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, October 1922-December 1922, 19 items. (10)
  Various letters, receipts, and subordinate cards for Supreme Lodge Knight of Gideon; letters include: to Signor Bradby from F.R. Savage of Peninsula Bank & Trust concerning a $25 note past due and endorsed for Tom Ferguson, to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth concerning wood inspection, to Annie Bradby from Nannie B. Taylor, to Elizabeth Bradby from Marguerite Mildred Walker, postcard to Annie Bradby from Emma Lee Burgess, postcard to Annie Bradby from “Sister [Mary T]yler, to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth concerning the sale and delivery of a turkey, postcard to Elizabeth Bradby from Ruth, postcard to Annie Bradby from Adele Beverly, postcard to Elizabeth Bradby from unknown, postcard to “Dear sister” Annie Bradby from unknown.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, January 1923-February 1923, 14 items. (11)
  Various letters, receipts, and mail-order correspondences; letters include: to “Dear Brother Seger” from “your Brother Philip Dandridge”, to Elizabeth Bradby from Marguerite Walker, to “My Dear Sister” Annie Bradby from Martha, to Signor Bradby from F.R. Savage of Peninsula Bank & Trust concerning a $85 note past due and endorsed for Andrew Jones, to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth concerning a wood order, to “My deaer belovest cousin” from Ella Mason Dandridge, to Annie Bradby from “your sister Martha”, to “Dear little sister” Nannie Bradby from “your Brother” Philip Dandridge, to Elizabeth Bradby “My Dear belovest cousin” from Lula B. Dandridge, to Annie Bradby from Jen, to Elizabeth Bradby from Marguerite Walker.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, March 1923-May 1923, 15 items. (12)
  Various letters, receipts, invoices, and mail-order correspondences; letters include: to “Mr. Bradley” from E.A. Tyler, postcard to Annie Bradby from Telorine [?] Clarke, to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth, to Earnest Jones from Levi Washington, to “the Pastor and Members of Mt. Zion Church” from Rev. T.H. Jones, to Signor Bradby from Tom Ferguson, to Annie Bradby from “sister Martha”, to Berkley Jones from “your aunt Martha”, to Annie Bradby from F. Haywood.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, June 1923, 12 items. (13)
  Letters and receipts; letters include: to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth, to “Signor Brady” from W.S. Bloxton of Continental Life Insurance Company, Inc. concerning an insurance claim, to Annie Bradby from Ella Dandridge, to Annie Bradby from Martha Walker, to “Mrs. Bradby and Elizabeth” from Florence Haywood, to Signor Bradby from J.A. Bozarth, postcard to Ernest Jones from J.L. Freeman.
- Letters, postcards, receipts, n.d., 21 items. (14)
  Letters, receipts, and invoices; letters include: postcard to unknown from unknown, postcard to Anna Bradby from E.B., postcard to A. Bradby from Florence Haywood, postcard to Annie “Bradley” from Isabel Test [?].
- Envelopes, 1890-1923, 23 items. (15)
  Envelopes addressed to John Jones, Signor Bradby, Annie Bradby, Elizabeth Bradby, Earnest Jones, New Zion Baptist Church, and E.K. Pettitt.
- Handwritten documents, 40 items. (16)
  Handwritten documents including notes, prescriptions, lists, poems, and school work.
- Printed material, 1922 and n.d., 40 items. (17)
  Printed materials including envelopes, “The Ladies Birthday Almanac” for 1922, and an Arm and Hammer “Book of Valuable Recipes” for 1922.